So, this is where you've
been hiding, El, huh?
[EL]
Mm.
[RICHARD] I was calling for
you just now. Didn't you hear?
I couldn't answer you.
Things are about to get good.
What are we gonna do about this
voracious appetite for books?
[RICHARD] Let's see.
What's the latest distraction?
[RICHARD]
A Sherlock Holmes mystery, huh.
I never could quite
understand the appeal
behind these detective stories.
[EL grunts]
[NARRATOR] Our story is
about the man who managed to
confound even the
world's greatest detective.
[NARRATOR]
The genius criminal mastermind
known as Professor Moriarty.
[RODDY panting]
[RODDY yelps]
[RODDY whimpers]
[chuckles]
[WILLIAM] Now there's
been a seventh victim.
"The townsfolk tremble at
the faceless assailant."
Thoughts?
A dreadful affair,
William. Simply awful.
Indeed.
They target young boys
for their amusement.
And afterwards, slaughter them.
It's hard to believe
a human could do that.
Most people don't want to
think a man capable of this.
It's a natural response.
"With the culprit
still at large,
the public grows dissatisfied
with law enforcement."
According to this,
there're no clues for
the police to follow.
Oh, but there are clues.
[LOUIS grunts]
[WILLIAM]
Some within this very article.
Looking at the child victims
and the occupations
of their parents,
do you notice the
emergence of a pattern?
[LOUIS] We have a clock smith,
a hatter, a jeweller,
a horse keeper, then a tailor.
[WILLIAM]
And whilst the father
of the latest victim's
business is unknown,
the deceased was
a messenger boy.
People aren't taken in by the
things outside of their view.
Most of us tend to
covet what we've seen.
For example, the omelettes
you make are exquisite.
Even when I'm working
in the field,
they're the first thing
I crave when hunger sets in.
Really? I'm touched.
Now, look. There.
There are people
across the globe
that likely have no knowledge
that a dish called
an omelette even exists.
Nor do I suspect
they'd have the
appetite for one.
Those occupations you listed--
the one element they all share
is that they frequently
find themselves
at the service of
nobles and aristocrats.
[LOUIS gasps]
When a nobleman purchases meat,
he'll send a servant
to the butcher shop
before ever going himself.
That said...
He will visit shops to purchase
his jewellery and clothing.
Even the stables,
because he has to board
his carriage there.
[WILLIAM] Naturally.
Providing opportunities
to encounter members
of their families.
It's not unusual
for a shopkeeper's son
to serve as an apprentice
for his father's business.
[LOUIS]
Nor would it be unusual to
encounter messenger boys
at prestigious clubs.
[WILLIAM] Indeed.
Whoever the murderer is,
he never has to wander far in
order to find his next victim.
He's successfully
fed his appetite
on those he comes across
within his social sphere.
We covet what we see every day.
Had it been a few victims,
a coincidence would have
been feasible. Not now.
After five bodies,
his modus operandi has
become all too apparent.
[LOUIS grunts]
You mean...?
I think it's about time
we involved ourselves
in this case, Louis.
[LOUIS]
It's odd.
There is one victim that
doesn't fit the profile.
An orphan who
slept on the streets.
What of him?
It is odd.
Noblemen and orphans--
two positions in society
that couldn't be further apart.
But they met.
The outlier might
just provide us
with the clue we need
to solve this mystery.
[door opens]
[EDEN]
Lord Albert.
I beg your pardon.
A pleasure to see you
in my shop, as always.
What might I be able
to help you with today?
The tuxedo you ordered?
Unfortunately, it isn't
quite finished yet.
[ALBERT] No. That's not
the reason for my visit.
Oh?
Condolences for the
fate that befell Roddy.
[grunts]
If you had let me know, I would
have attended his funeral.
Out of the question.
An earl such as yourself,
coming to a funeral
for commoners?
It'd be undignified!
Imagine what people would say.
[ALBERT]
You're looking a bit careworn.
Shouldn't you be
getting some rest?
I appreciate
your concern, truly.
You see, work is one
of the few retreats
from this overwhelming grief.
[ALBERT] I saw him here in
the store a number of times.
Roddy was a good lad.
[EDEN]
He was.
Forgive a father
and his reminiscing,
but there wasn't a more
obedient or dutiful boy.
For him to meet
such a gruesome end,
it makes you question if there's
true justice in this world.
I wonder...
[ALBERT]
Hm?
[EDEN] ...what I'd do
to the one who did this.
[BOY 1A grunts]
[grunting]
[accordion groans]
[sighs]
[gasps, chuckles]
If you have a moment,
I'd like to have a word.
You don't mind, do you?
[BOY 1A] Sorry for how I'm
lackin' in table manners, sir.
So, what is it
you wanted to ask me?
[WILLIAM] That concertina didn't
always belong to you, did it?
[BOY 1A gulps]
Even though it's
your livelihood,
you're not particularly skilled
when it comes to playing it.
Uh! You're not the police
or something, are you?
If I were, would I have
gone through the trouble of
bringing you to this place?
[BOY 1A]
You got a point.
A real bobby woulda
hauled me down
to the station
without sayin' a word.
That 'ol thing used
to belong to Cass.
[WILLIAM gasps]
[BOY 1A] You've heard
about the murders, right?
Don't know why they chose him,
but he was killed
like the others.
Anyway, I was his mate.
So, it only seemed fittin'
that I inherit his business.
Had to relocate though,
seeing how that
corner was cursed.
On that note,
where exactly did
Cass routinely perform?
[BOY 1A]
Hm?
Why? There's nothin' there.
But if you really wanna go,
head two streets over.
[WILLIAM]
Was he spotted from a carriage?
No. The boy was chosen as prey.
Meaning the hunter had the
opportunity to study him.
[WILLIAM grunts]
[LOUIS] Then, the killer
saw him from the window?
That is the most
likely scenario, yes.
So, he gazed down at the square,
unable to tear his eyes away
from that unfortunate waif.
And then he struck.
Have you found out
who owns the house?
[WILLIAM] Actually,
it's not a private residence.
The building is where
the Gastros Club meets.
[ALBERT]
The Gastros Club?
That's a place frequented
by wealthy connoisseurs
of good food.
Ah. It sounds as though you're
familiar with them, Albert.
[ALBERT] Oh, just talk,
mostly unflattering.
Still, I do have a
number of acquaintances
who are members there.
That's quite
advantageous for us.
In order to join their circle
a member must refer you.
You think we'll find
him there, don't you?
Indeed.
Considering the number of
indicators pointing us there,
we can't very well
ignore the place.
Well then,
in that case, we may
be able to provide Eden
with a chance for
the vengeance he desires.
[WILLIAM]
Ah, you there.
[SERVER 1A]
Sir, what can I do for you?
Would you mind telling me
who the gentleman is that
always sits by the window?
[SERVER 1A]
Certainly.
That would be
the Earl of Argleton.
He's one of the club's founding
members from what I'm told.
Makes sense. If the man
helped found the place,
then I would say he's free to
reserve any seat he pleases.
Actually, sir, we
have no reservations.
However, I would say
that is his preferred chair
whenever it's available.
[WILLIAM]
Pardon, your lordship.
[grunts]
[WILLIAM]
It is a pleasure to meet you.
My name is William
James Moriarty.
Do we have some sort
of business I'm unaware of?
[WILLIAM]
Hardly that.
There's nothing I require.
See, I noticed you sitting
over here, staring listlessly,
and thought I might engage you
in casual conversation.
Well, despite appearances,
I'm actually--
That is a wonderful suit.
You had it tailored
at Eden's, didn't you?
And that ring is one of a kind.
The mounting is quite elaborate.
If I had to guess,
I'd say the design was
by Goldstein Jewellers.
You're not a detective, are you?
You have quite
the observant eye.
I can go on, if it amuses you.
Based on your
pocket watch chain,
I would say it came from
R. Masters Clock Smith.
Am I correct?
My word.
You deduced that without even
laying eyes on the timepiece.
Incredible.
[WILLIAM]
I haven't seen your hat either,
but I imagine it's
from Morgan Brothers.
Nor your horses,
which are no doubt stabled
at the Shannon Racing Club.
[ARGLETON grunts]
Furthermore, as of late,
your musical interests
have moved towards
the concertina.
[ARGLETON gasps]
And I'll wager you prefer
the meat of young hares.
Tender--not fully developed.
So fresh it practically
drips with blood,
which you take the time
to savour, no doubt.
Nice and slow.
One more observation.
You must be terrible
at playing cards.
[gasps]
Considering how your thoughts
are clearly reflected
on your face.
Excuse me, but there's an
urgent matter I must attend to.
[grunts]
You're here to find out
more about me, no doubt.
Or perhaps
to do something more severe.
[growls]
[WILLIAM] Based on that stance,
you're accustomed to fisticuffs.
But it's your brain
that needs exercise.
After all,
this won't be the same
as kidnapping
defenseless children.
[gasps]
What a poker face. Revealing,
much like your master's.
[growls]
There are several questions
I'd like to ask you.
That is, if you
can spare the time.
[door opens]
Welcome to Eden's. [gasps]
Lord Albert! How are you, sir?
[ALBERT] Mister Eden in?
Well, he's in his office, but--
[door opens]
Lord Albert, welcome back.
What brings you to
my shop at such an hour?
I've grown close to someone
and wanted to ask
her out for dinner.
I figured it was best to stop
by and order something new.
It's a rather detailed
request, I'm afraid.
You came to the right place.
Step into my office
and we'll talk about it.
If you're finished out here,
feel free to go home.
[EMPLOYEE 1A]
Thank you, sir.
[ARGLETON grunts]
[WILLIAM]
Apologies, your lordship.
I admit these methods
are somewhat draconian,
but I doubt you'd
have met me voluntarily.
Slight correction.
It's actually this gentleman
who was adamant about
arranging some time
alone with you.
It's been far too long, my lord.
[ARGLETON yelps]
[EDEN]
Sir William.
I want your guarantee that
you can supply me what I want.
Give me your word!
Mister Eden.
In this twisted
world we live in,
the thing you're proposing,
no matter how justified,
is still considered a crime
in the eyes of the law.
Even so, are you committed
to going through with it?
[EDEN]
Mm.
[WILLIAM]
Very well then.
Leave it to me.
I've accepted your request.
Crime consultant William
James Moriarty is on the case.
[ARGLETON yelps]
Please be quick about it.
I only have one cigarette on me.
[bell tolling]
[WILLIAM]
Mister Eden?
[EDEN grunts]
Come. I think we should be off.
[LOUIS] Beautiful morning,
isn't it, William?
Are there any interesting
headlines in today's paper?
[WILLIAM]
Appears not.
No mention of a debaucherous
earl, his coachman,
or the discovery of their
brutally mutilated bodies.
For the best.
That would certainly set London
hopping, don't you think?
I quite agree.
[WILLIAM] If you remove all
traces of an incident,
then it's as if it never
occurred in the first place.
In other words...
...you commit the perfect crime.
[WILLIAM] Next time on
Moriarty the Patriot  .
"The Scarlet Eyes. Act One."